Prey for the living.
The 13th Warrior is a adventure, history, action
film directed by John McTiernan.
A Muslim ambassador exiled from his homeland joins a group of Vikings,
initially offended by their behavior but growing to respect them.
As they travel together, they learn of a legendary evil closing in
and must unite to confront this formidable force.
Ahmed Ibh Fahdlan, played by Antonio Banderas.
Queen Weilew, played by Diane Venora.
Herger (Joyous), played by Dennis Storhøi.
Buliwyf, played by Vladimir Kulich.
Melchisidek, played by Omar Sharif.
Wigliff (King's Son), played by Anders T. Andersen.
The 13th Warrior is a 1999 American historical fiction action film based on Michael Crichton's 1976 novel Eaters of the Dead, which is
a loose adaptation of the tale of Beowulf combined with Ahmad ibn Fadlan's historical account of the Volga Vikings.
It stars Antonio Banderas as Ahmad ibn Fadlan (credited as Ahmed ibn
Fahdlan), as well as Diane Venora and Omar Sharif.
It was directed by John McTiernan; Crichton directed some uncredited reshoots.
The film was produced by McTiernan, Crichton, and Ned Dowd, with Andrew G.
Vajna, James Biggam and Ethan Dubrow as executive producers.
Production and marketing costs reportedly ranged from $100–$160 million, but it grossed $61 million at the box
office worldwide, becoming the biggest box-office bomb of 1999, with losses of up to $129 million.
Despite its critical and box office failure, the film has since cultivated a devoted cult
following, and is credited with pioneering a Muslim hero in Hollywood blockbusters.
The film explores themes of witch, mission, based
on novel or book, kingdom, arabian.
The tone is dark.